eastershow.com.au 2017-05-19

# PRIVACY POLICY

                                    PRIVACY POLICY
The RAS recognises the importance of privacy and is committed to protecting the information you
provide to us. RAS complies with the Australian Privacy Principles and the purpose of this Privacy
Policy is to clearly communicate to you how the RAS collects, holds, uses and disclosed personal
information in accordance with the provisions as contained in the:
     -   Privacy Act 1988 (Cth), and
     -   Privacy Amendment (Enhancing Privacy Protection) Act 2012.
For the purpose of this Privacy Policy the definition of the ‘RAS’ includes:
RAS of NSW Foundation Limited ABN 84 124 177 608; and
Royal Agricultural Society of NSW ABN 69 793 644 351
Trading as:      Sydney Royal
                 Sydney Showground
                 Sydney Royal Easter Show
                 Australasian Animal Registry
The RAS is a not for profit entity with the principal aim of promoting, fostering and encouraging the
development of agricultural pursuits. The RAS pursues this aim via the annual Sydney Royal Easter
Show, conducting the Sydney Royal Fine Food and Wine Shows, and acts as a venue for the holding
of events such as festivals, exhibitions, conferences, entertainment activities and functions.
The RAS also manages the RAS of NSW Foundation which operates for the purpose of granting funds
to education, sustainable agriculture and rural projects in accordance with the overarching
framework of the mission, values and purposes of the RAS.
By providing personal information to the RAS and by having access to this Privacy Policy, you
consent to the RAS collecting, holding, using and disclosing personal information in accordance
with this policy.
The Purpose of the Collection
The RAS will provide a ‘Collection Statement’ at the point of collection informing you of the reason
why the information is being collected. The point of collection is usually an Entry Form, Registration
Form, online or in person. The information collected will be used for the primary purpose detailed in
the Collection Statement, and any secondary purpose to which you have consented. The RAS will not
disclose information for another purpose unless you have consented to the disclosure in the normal
course of the service or good we are providing to you, or unless it is required to be disclosed by law.
In some instances, the RAS uses contractors and suppliers to provide the service to which you have
consented, which will require disclosure of your personal information to these third parties. The
third parties used are also bound by the Australian Privacy Principles, or if they are an international
company, are bound by contract to adhere to the Australian Privacy Principles in order to protect
the information.
(09/16)

Access, Amendments and Complaints
Access to this Privacy Policy is free, it is available online at:
 www.rasnsw.com.au,
www.sydneyshowground.com.au
You may also request a hardcopy of the Privacy Policy by contacting our Privacy Officer. You can
request access to and alteration of personal information concerning yourself in accordance with the
Privacy Laws. You may contact the RAS Privacy Officer by the following methods:
Telephone         (02) 9704 1111
 Mail             RAS Locked Bag 4317, Sydney Olympic Park NSW 2127.
Email             privacy@rasnsw.com.au
You can request that your personal information be corrected. You can also request that your
account be deleted. You may contact us at any time to request to opt out of any electronic,
telephone or other form of direct marking. There will be an ‘Opt Out’ link at the bottom of each
email.
The Privacy Officer will deal with all initial queries and complaints. If you are not content with the
way in which our Privacy Officer has dealt with your issue or if you have not received a response
within 30 days, and you wish to lodge a formal written complaint to the General Manager. The
General Manager will provide a written response to you within 30 days. You may address the matter
to:               General Manager, Corporate Services,
                  1 Showground Road, Sydney Olympic Park, 2127.
If you are not content with the response from the RAS General Manager, you may wish to raise the
issue with an external complaint body such as Office of Australian Information Commissioner (OAIC).
By email          enquiries@oaic.gov.au
By telephone (02) 9284 9666
By post           Office of Australian Information Commissioner
                 GPO Box 5218,
                 Sydney NSW 2001
Types of Personal Information
The information you provide us may include:
     (a) Personal information that is required in order to facilitate an application, purchase a
         product, use a particular service or participate in an activity.
     (b) Personal information that is optional. This information is not required but will always be
         directly related to the RAS’s functions and activities. This information enables the RAS to
         improve or maintain the functions and activities we offer you.
     (c) Sensitive Information that is required in order to process financial payments for example.
         This information will be kept only for the purpose of dealing with the transaction or matter.
(09/16)

Consent - You could be asked to confirm that you would like to receive updates or will agree to a
particular activity. If all of the required personal information is not provided, then RAS might not be
able to accept an application by an individual to participate in the competition. Where an application
is made by a company entity, the company may provide the personal information of key employees
or directors who are deemed to have consented to the release of their names and employment title
as provided by the employer.
Pseudonyms – In circumstances where your legal name is not required, such as carnival update
emails, you may use a pseudonym. However, in most cases your consent, payment or competition
entry will require your legal name.
Use of Personal Information
Different departments of the RAS uses information collected for different purposes, and you consent
to your information being disclosed when necessary and legal to do so in order to provide the
service or good that you require.
To protect from misuse or loss, the RAS takes all reasonable steps in each case to protect the
personal information provided in different circumstances. Examples of use and disclosure are as
follows:
     1) Membership – RAS is a membership society and Members details are held securely. Your
         information will be used to send you direct mail for RAS publications (such as the RAS
         Times), or RAS related promotions, events, discounts to which you have consented.
         Information about links to family members or commercial opportunities will be linked in
         your membership account, and details provided by other family members may be collected
         for junior and youth accounts.
     2) Sydney Showground – Information is collected to contract with you for the hire of venues
         on the Showground. Information may be collected from suppliers or contractors who are
         providing services for the event being held. In order to run a smooth event, RAS will disclose
         information to other involved parties in order to efficiently coordinate the event. If you
         require any documents to remain confidential, please inform RAS staff and mark the
         documents clearly on the front page. Deposits and pre-payment of operational services are
         often required so we keep your financial information secure until the end of the event when
         the refund and settlement of your account can be made.
     3) Sydney Royal Competitions – The competitions for the Easter Show and Wine, Dairy & Fine
         Food Shows will all require personal information to be collected in order to hold the
         competition, assess entries, create event timetables and schedules, to run the competition
         and provide prize money cheques to the winners. During the competitions your personal
         information will be listed in competition schedules and displayed on the internet. Winners of
         competitions may be interviewed and your details will be kept in the RAS archives and kept
         in the History Centre.
(09/16)

     4) Sydney Royal Easter Show – In addition to the Sydney Royal Competitions held, there are
        many contractors, commercial exhibitors and carnival licensees who need to provide
        personal information in order for the RAS to contract with you. Most transactions require
        payment in which your legal name will be required. RAS will hold your information securely
        and restrict access to only those who are involved in the transaction. Your information may
        be disclosed to third party contractors or suppliers who need to contact you for Easter Show
        related services to be provided.
     5) Australasian Animal Registry (AAR) – The AAR database is held for the purpose of matching
        micro-chip numbers implanted in animals with the personal information of person who is
        either the legal owner of the animal, or the person who is responsible for the daily care and
        control of the animal. The AAR database is not a register of proprietary ownership. RAS will
        disclose this information to Councils, government agencies or animal welfare organisations
        such as the RSPCA, who are trying to re-unite the animal with its owner. Disclosure may also
        be required by law, to trace the owners of a dangerous dog for example.
     6) RAS of NSW Foundation – The Foundation is the charitable arm of the RAS and requests for
        donations or details of fund raising events or projects may be sent to you. Personal details
        will be collected on paper forms and also through online procedures. The details of
        unsuccessful applicants will be held for up to 7 years and will be sent details of other
        opportunities for scholarships or grants. The recipients of scholarships and grants may have
        disclosure of their name, suburb, career and educational information disclosed as part of the
        conditions of the award.
     7) Other RAS Data – The RAS Corporate Services may use your information for billing purposes,
        and collecting debts and may conduct credit checks on entities when appropriate. Human
        Resources collect personal information for recruitment purposes which will be destroyed
        securely after a reasonable time. The RAS may want to conduct market research to develop
        internal systems or upgrade processes in which your data may be used. The RAS also runs
        the RAS Heritage Centre in which documents and trophies which may hold your personal
        information will be stored and released to Members or the media as reasonably required.
        Cross-border disclosure may also be required for benchmarking or external storage of
        information, in which case having access to this Privacy Policy and providing your
        information is deemed to be consent to the cross-border disclosure.
     8)  Third Parties and Cookies - The RAS use third party application tracking services such as
        Google Analytics and Inspectlet to help understand the use of our Services and Site(s).
        Information collected by Google is governed by Google's Privacy Policy
        [https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/]. We use the tool Inspectlet to analyse
        the activities of visitors to our websites, and Inspectlet’s authorised use of cookies and other
        tracking technologies enable it to have access to Personal Information of visitors to our
        website. This tracking is to understand how our users interact with our products and
        services. Inspectlet does not capture any personal information entered into any input form
        on our website including but not limited to names, email addresses, address information or
        payment information. Such access to and use of Personal Information by Inspectlet is
        governed by Inspectlet’s Privacy Policy [https://www.inspectlet.com/legal#privacy].
(09/16)

The types of personal information collected in each RAS department is detailed on the following
page.
(09/16)

                                          Sydney
                                          Royal        Sydney       RES        Carnival                       Corporate
  Type of Information          Membership Competitions Showground   Commercial Riders Club AAR   Foundation   Services
  First Name                      Yes         Yes          Yes          Yes        Yes       Yes     Yes           Yes
  Surname                         Yes         Yes          Yes          Yes                  Yes     Yes           Yes
  Gender                          Yes         Yes          Yes          Yes
  Date of Birth                   Yes         Yes      As Necessary                Yes                        As Necessary
  Phone                           Yes         Yes          Yes          Yes                  Yes     Yes           Yes
  Email                           Yes         Yes          Yes          Yes        Yes       Yes     Yes           Yes
  Postal Address                  Yes         Yes          Yes          Yes    Suburb only   Yes     Yes           Yes
  Occupation                              As Necessary     Yes          Yes                      As Necessary      Yes
  Employer                                As Necessary     Yes          Yes                      As Necessary      Yes
  Alternate contact for Health
  and Safety                              As Necessary     Yes          Yes                                   As Necessary
  Credit Card                     Yes         Yes          Yes          Yes                  Yes     Yes           Yes
                                                                        As
  Bank Account                                Yes          Yes       Necessary                       Yes           Yes
                                                                        As
  Animals under your care                     Yes                    Necessary               Yes
  Password                                                                                   Yes                   Yes
  Drivers Licence (for working
  with children check)                        Yes                       Yes                                   As Necessary
  Details about your
  children/family                 Yes         Yes                                                                  Yes
  Alternate contact for AAR                                                                  Yes
(09/16)
